多米尼加共和国
DOMINICAN REPUBLIC
准备好了
All right, we're good to go.
- 好了吗？ - 没问题
- You got this? - You bet your ass, bubba.
大赚一笔吧！
Let's make some money!
各就各位！
Everyone in position.
我还以为我们要抢银行
l thought we'd be robbing banks by now,
而不是在这前不着村后不着店 的地方抢油罐车
not some gas truck in the middle of nowhere.
在这 石油就是黄金
Down here, gas is gold, bubba.
是啊 可是银行不会乱跑
Yeah, But banks don't move.
每次你靠近银行 我们都要把你从牢里弄出来
Anytime you get near a bank...we have to break your ass out of prison.
别聊了 开始干活
Kill the chatter! Game time.
我可不想惹恼他 伙计们
l wouldn't piss him off, guys.
听到啦
Yeah, yeah, I hear you.
贪吃的家伙
Hey, you greedy bitch!
我们要麻利点
Okay, guys, we're gonna have to hit this hard and fast.
还有4公里就下坡了
We got four K left before the downgrade.
接好了！
Locked and loaded!
都是你的 韩
This is all you, Han.
液体黄金
Liquid gold.
我们搞定了
We're clear.
提戈 该你们了
Okay, T, you're up.
看看你6次以内能否搞定
Let's see if you can get it under six tries this time, huh, T?
说什么呢 这回一次搞定
What are you talking about? I'll do it in one try!
三次差不多 好啦 提戈 动真格的了
Lt's more like three. Come on, Tego, keep it real.
还剩1公里 前面没路了 动作快点 老弟
Just one K left. We're running out of road. Get in there, brother.
明白
I got it, I got it.
糟糕！
Shit!
提戈 快松开！
T, cut loose! Unhitch, unhitch!
- 别犯傻 松开挂钩！ - 你以为我在干什么！
- Don't be crazy.lose your load! - What do you think I'm trying to do?
笨蛋 快松开！
...idiot,just release!
- 喷那个挂钩！ - 我没有锤子！
- Spray that hitch! - I don't have a hammer!
做吧！
Just do it!
抓紧！抓紧！
Hold on! Hold on!
不！
No shit!
抓紧点！
Hold onto something tight!
莱蒂！
Letty!
- 抓住我的手！ - 我够不到！
- Give me your hand! - I can't reach!
跳！
You got to jump!
Jump!
莱蒂 跳！
Letty, jump!
我接着你！
I've got you!
多姆…
Dom...
多姆？
Dom?
多姆！
Dom!
速 度 与 激 情 4
普莱莫在机场当保安
Mi primo is running security on the airbase.
他说要来几架运油机
Says that there's going to be a couple of refueling planes arriving.
你好吗？
HAN: How you doing?
钱！钱！
OMAR: Money, money!
不错
Good.
为什么你那一叠总比我的厚？
OMAR: Yo, why your stack is bigger than mine always?
我是大号的 伙计
I'm supersized, baby.
找点乐子去
Go have fun.
警察突击了我们在巴拉科阿的修车厂
Cops just raided our garage in Baracoa.
他们要抓的是你
They were real interested in you.
我们刚刚又给他们留下了线索
Heat's on and we just sent up a flare that's gonna lead them right to us.
我们明早就离开这
l say we move out first thing in the morning.
不 他们要抓的是我
Nah, it's me they want.
如果他们抓住我
And if they catch me,
他们会把与我有牵连的人都投入大牢
they're throwing big numbers at anybody with me.
韩 我们做得不错
Han, we had a good run.
你该去做些自己的事情了
Time for you to go do your own thing.
听说他们在东京很疯狂
Heard they're doing some crazy shit in Tokyo.
见到莱蒂了吗？
Have you seen Letty?
她在那
There she is.
我听说里约每年这时候很美
I hear Rio is nice this time of year.
警察追得越来越紧
The cops are getting hungrier.
这就是我们的生活
Then I guess we're doing our job.
我是个移动的目标
I'm a walking target.
我不想被抓住的时候让你受牵连
I don't want you around when they catch up to me.
“不开车就去死” 还记得吗？
"Ride or die," remember?
多姆 我们干这行多久了？
Dom, how long have we been doing this?
突然之间 凭空就说这很危险了？
And now all of a sudden, out of nowhere, it's too dangerous?
好啦
Come on.
我们能化险为夷的 一向如此
We'll figure it out. We always do.
洛杉矶市区
DOWNTOWN LOS ANGELES
- 我什么都不知道！ - 告诉我他的名字！
- I don't know shit! - Give me a name!
- I don't know shit, man! - Give me a name!
大卫・帕克！他就是你要找的人！
David Park! David Park's the guy you want!
别开枪！
Please!
感谢上帝 听着 他没发火因为昨天他偷懒没锻炼
Thank God. Listen, he's in a mood because yesterday was his cheat day,
今天 有人拿来了甜甜圈
and then today, some genius brought in donuts.
很好
Great.
对不起来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
你在市区闹运之后就投诉不断
Complaints keep rolling in after your little downtown Olympics, O'Conner.
告诉我给你复职不是错误
Tell me that reinstating you wasn't a mistake.
- 我拿到个名字 大卫・帕克 - 就这个？
- I got a name. David Park. - That's it?
就听到个大卫・帕克？
That's all you got? David Park?
从这窗户扔出去块点心 能砸到50个大卫・帕克
I could throw a fortune cookie out this window and hit 50 David Parks right now.
- 是韩国人 不是中国人 - 随便
- It's Korean, not Chinese. - Whatever.
帕克召集街头车手给布拉加运货
Park is a scout that recruits street racers to be mules for the Braga cartel.
我们找到帕克 就能将他们一网打尽
We find Park, and we bust the bad guys.
巴拿马 巴拿马城
PANAMA CITY,PANAMA
多姆
Dom.
米娅 我说过不要打到这里来
Mia, I told you not to call me here.
多姆 是莱蒂
Dom, it's Letty.
遇害了
She's been murdered.
我们到这里作最后致意…
We have gathered here to pay our final respects to...
我们来追忆她的旅程…
Let us reflect on her journey...
"上帝是我的牧师 我本不需要 他使我接受…"
"The Lord is my shepherd, I shall not want. He makes me lie down..."
面部识别程序在特伦托
Facial recognition software matched Toretto
入境10分钟后发现了他
about 1 0 minutes after he crossed the border.
我不明白
I don't get it.
我以为他会来的
I thought he'd show.
我告诉你不要来的 他们在监视这里
I told you not to come. They're staking the place out.
- 如果他们发现你… - 不会的
- If they find you... - They won't.
好啦 瞧瞧你
Come on. Look at you.
莱蒂不让他们处理掉它
Letty wouldn't let them junk it.
即便它是个诅咒
Even though it is a goddamn curse.
她回来以后 就到这里
When she came back, she was always in here,
夜以继日地改进它
working on it day and night.
真是不可思议
It was weird.
就好像她知道你会回来
It was like she knew you were coming back.
我要看看出事现场
I want to see the crash site.
我刚和副局长通过电话
I just got off the phone with Deputy Director Lawson.
如果我们72小时内在布拉加的案子上还没进展
If we don't make serious inroads into the Braga case in the next 72 hours,
我们就都下岗了
they're gonna shut us down.
我知道是新来的 但是为什么那么急？
I know I'm a newbie here, but why the clock now?
因为已经两年了
Because it's been two years,
我们派去卧底的三个探员
and the last three agents we sent to infiltrate his organization
都裹着尸袋回来的
came back in body bags.
他运入境的海洛因比埃斯科巴10年的都多
He's moved more heroin across the border than Escobar did in 1 0 years.
这家伙成为国家安全最大的威胁之一
This guy is becoming one of our biggest national threats,
我们连他的照片都没有
and we don't even have a picture of him.
没有指纹！连出生日期都不知道！
We don't have prints! Not even a goddamn DOB!
大卫・帕克是什么人？
What's the status on David Park?
他是我们潜入布拉加组织的通行证？
lsn't he our ticket into the Braga organization?
我们通过数据库搜索 按可能性排序
We're running the name through city and county databases, sorting the possibilities.
已经有500个了
We've got over 500 already.
帕克不重要 对我来说就是个小混混
Park's insignificant. Sounds like another jerk-off to me.
不是的 没有帕克介绍 布拉加不会让车手给他送货
It's not. Without Park, Braga wouldn't have drivers to move his shipments.
监视交通 非法改装
Cross-check traffic. lllegal modifications.
街头赛车 这家伙肯定有记录 我们会抓住他
Street racing. This guy will definitely have a record. We'll find him.
最好如此
We better.
知道吗？
What do you know?
你那小子特伦托的红色雪佛兰 在他家附近出现
Your boy Toretto's red Chevelle has been spotted in his old neighborhood.
我要把他抓来
I'm going to bring his ass in.
你抓不到的
Not in your car you're not.
就在前面
It's straight ahead.
你在那发现了什么
You found something back there.
地面上有烧焦的痕迹
There were burn marks on the ground.
只可能是硝基甲烷造成的
The kind that could only be caused by nitrometh.
洛杉矶只有一家卖这个
There's only one guy in all of L.A. that sells that.
无论怎样她都不会复生 多姆
Nothing you can do is gonna bring her back, Dom.
如果我是莱蒂 我会要你…
If I were Letty, I would ask you...
不 我求你 忘掉它吧
No, I would beg you, please, let this go.
否则就太迟了
Before it's too late.
已经太迟了
It's already too late.
我爱你
I love you.
特伦托小姐
Miss Toretto.
我叫迈克尔・斯特萨克 联邦调查局的
I'm Michael Stasiak, FBl.
我们需要谈谈
Let's you and I have a little chat.
我是证据组的福赛斯
Hi. This is Forsythe in Evidence.
我要斯特萨克来登记证人
I need Stasiak down here right away to sign some greenies.
谢谢
Thanks.
嘿
Hi. Hey.
我把范围缩小到50个大卫・帕克
Okay, I narrowed it down to 50 or so David Parks.
你要做的是查清他们每个的底细
What I'd like you to do is run the make and model on each one of them.
- 明白？ - 好的
- All right? - Okay. All right.
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿 泰勒 我们换班了
Hey, Tyler, we got a transfer.
和我来
You want to come with me?
特伦托
Toretto.
你什么时候回来的？
When'd you get back in town?
我在找一辆你改造过引擎的车
I'm looking for a car you did an engine mod on.
硝基甲烷油箱 福特全尺寸 大陆牌轮胎
Nitromethane tank. Ford full-size. Continental tires.
听着 你在干什么？ 就这样大摇大摆地进来？
Look, what are you doing, coming in here like this, huh?
这不再是你的地盘了 老大
This ain't your scene anymore, boss.
别再来找我
Don't ever put your hands on me again, okay?
代我向你妹妹问好
Say hi to your sister for me.
一个韩国小子 大卫・帕克
A Korean kid brought it in. David Park.
绿色福特都灵车
It's a green Ford Torino.
别砸我！
Please don't drop this on me!
我吃完了
I'm almost done.
何不告诉我你为何带我到这来
Why don't you tell me why you dragged me here, Brian?
你知道他们要抓多姆 也许更糟
You know they're going to capture Dom. Maybe worse.
我不想你卷入这件事 所以离他远点
I don't want you getting tangled up in this. So stay away from him.
5年了 这就是你要对我说的？
That's what you have to say to me after five years?
突然间 你就关心起我了
All of a sudden, you care what happens to me.
我原来对不起你
What I did to you was wrong.
我很遗憾 那是… 我所做的最困难的事情
I'm sorry. It was... It was the hardest thing I've ever had to do.
我也很遗憾 布莱恩
I'm sorry, too, Brian.
我很遗憾你闯进我家 假装爱我
I'm so sorry that you had to come into my home and pretend to love me.
我很遗憾你把我家搞得四分五裂
I'm so sorry that you ripped my family apart.
我非常遗憾这对你很难
I'm very sorry that that was hard for you.
我对你撒了谎
I lied to you.
我对多姆撒了谎 对所有人撒了谎
I lied to Dom. I lied to everybody.
这是我拿手的 因此联邦调查局招我进去
That's what I do best. It's why the Feds recruited me.
也许你在对自己撒谎
Maybe you're lying to yourself.
也许你不是装作坏人的好人
Maybe you're not the good guy pretending to be a bad guy.
也许你是装作好人的坏人
Maybe you're the bad guy pretending to be the good guy.
你想过吗
You ever think about that?
每天都想
Every day.
我总在想
I always wondered,
那天你为什么让我哥哥走？
why did you let my brother go that day?
我不知道
I don't know.
唉
Shit.
布莱恩！
Brian!
我核查了大卫・帕克 列出了可能的名单
I got the cross-checks on David Park back and have a list of possibles.
- 上面有谁？ - 45岁男性 开06款Scion
- What do you got? - All right. A 45-year-old male in a '06 Scion
- 有三张罚单 - 不是他
- with three reckless driving tickets. - No.
- 01款雪佛兰塔荷 - 不是
- An '01 Chevy Tahoe. - No.
两辆Mini Cooper 06和07款 丰田混合车
Two Mini Coopers, a '06 and a '07, a Toyota hybrid.
- 不是 - 98款Saturn 95款Sebring
- Hell no. - A '98 Saturn, a '95 Sebring.
98款尼桑240 非法改装过
A '98 Nissan 240 with an illegal mod.
等等 就是它
Wait. That's it.
- 哪个？ - 非法改装的尼桑240
- What? - The 240 with the illegal mod.
- 你怎么知道 - 因为是我会开的
- How do you know? - 'Cause that's something I'd drive.
不要！
Don't! Don't! Don't!
绿色都灵车 烧硝基甲烷
Green Torino, running nitro.
- 谁的车？ - 我不知道
- Whose car? - I don't know, man.
我只是中间人 我发誓！ 我只是中间人
I'm just the middleman. I swear! I'm just the middleman!
等等
Wait, wait, wait.
我不知道 我发誓 我只是给布拉加开车的
I don't know shit, man. I swear. I just run cars for Braga, all right?
我能做的只有让你去参赛！ 就这些！
All I can do is get you in the race! That's all I can do!
什么比赛？
What race?
救命！抓住啊！
Help! Come on, hold on!
把我拉上去 快！
Let me up, man! Come on!
快点啊！我什么都不知道！拉我上去！
Come on, man, I don't know shit! Just let me up!
我说了 你要和布拉加去谈！
I told you, you got to talk to Braga!
把他拉上来 多姆
Bring him up, Dom.
天啊！别放下我！我只知道这些！
God! Don't drop me! That's all I know!
把他拉上来
Bring him up.
你来抓我的 奥康纳？
You here to take me in, O'Conner?
- 靠！ - 闭嘴！
- Shit! Shit! - Shut up!
莱蒂也是我的朋友
Letty was my friend, too.
你没有朋友
You weren't anyone's friend.
你们能不能以后再谈这个？ 快把我拉上去！
Yo, can you guys talk about this later? Now pull my ass up!
她在为这个布拉加做事 后来出了情况
She was running for this guy, Braga, and things went bad.
求求你！
Please!
我要抓住这帮人 多姆
I'm going to get these guys, Dom.
让我来做我的工作 把他拉上来
Now let me do my job and bring him up.
我要杀了布拉加
I'm going to kill this Braga.
天啊！
God!
还有挡我道的人
And anyone else who gets in my way.
嘿！
Hey!
别放手！
Don't let go.
奥康纳！
O'Conner!
奥康纳！如果你再放走我的证人…
O'Conner! If you ever release a witness of mine again...
- 够了！ - 别碰我
- That's enough! - Don't touch me.
- 我没事 - 够了
- I'm fine! - That's enough.
- 你完了 奥康纳！ - 够了！
- You're through, O'Conner! - I said that's enough!
斯特萨克 去洗洗
Stasiak, go get yourself cleaned up.
什么？他先打我的 你…
What? He hit me first! You...
这不是童子军！
This isn't the Cub Scouts!
快去！血滴到我的地板了
Now, go on! You're bleeding on my floor.
奥康纳？你知道警察和罪犯的区别吗？
O'Conner, do you know the difference between a cop and a criminal?
- 什么？ - 主观上的判断
- What? - One bad judgment call.
规矩点 孩子
Keep your shit in line, son.
祝你好运
Have a good time.
坐下
Take a seat.
好消息 内线说布拉加的二把手 雷蒙・坎波斯
Good news. We have intel that Braga's number two, Ramon Campos,
明晚要在韩国城举行街头车赛
will hold a street race in Koreatown tomorrow night
为他的队伍选拔人才
to fill a slot on his team.
他们从前面的比赛中已经选中三个
They've already chosen three drivers from previous races.
我们最新的线人 大卫・帕克
Our newest informant, Mr. David Park,
让我们能够进入比赛
has been kind enough to get us into the race.
奥康纳 该你了
O'Conner, you're up.
我猜是赢家获得位子
Let me guess, winner gets the slot.
这就是本市扣押的车辆
All right, so these are all the imports the city has in impound.
- 不错 - 挑一辆吧
- Okay, nice. - Pick your poison.
2226号 我曾撞毁过一辆
All right, 2206. I crashed one of those.
3418和2765号
341 8 and 2765.
你选哪辆？
Okay, so which one do you want?
都要了
I want them all.
标准跟踪系统
Standard issue tracking device.
头要一直知道你在哪
Boss wants to know where you are at all times.
你想玩玩吗？
You want to play with it?
嘿！
Hey!
你在看什么 脓包？
What are you looking at, nutsack?
不知道 你说呢
I don't know. You tell me.
车手想要德怀特的东西
The racer wants what Dwight's got.
但是姑娘们 德怀特已经入选了
See, but, ladies, Dwight's already on the team.
你要想给布拉加开车的话得快点
You got to be fast if you want to drive for Braga.
- 有问题吗？ - 没
- Is there a problem here? - No.
你是帕克找来的吧？
You one of Park's guys, blondie?
是的
Yeah. Yeah, I am.
跟我来
Follow me.
回头见 小子
See you later, punk.
你也是 小子
You, too, punk.
一击命中！
BulI's-eye, co?o, come on!
总能做到
We can do this all day.
你们都知道为什么到这来
You all know why you're here.
好的车手
Good drivers
实在太多了
are a dime a dozen.
靠开车泡妞的人太多了
Man, every corner's got a chingadera tuner racing for pinks.
那不是布拉加让我找的
That's not what Braga has got me looking for.
布拉加要的是能把一切抛在脑后的人
Braga wants someone that would sell their abuelita to be behind the wheel.
不是规规矩矩地开跑车
Someone that drives their 1 0-second cars not in a straight line,
而是穿过没人能去的地方
but to push it and make it through places no one else would take it.
真正的车手
Real drivers.
我们运什么？
So, what are we hauling?
布拉加付钱 你没必要知道
For the money Braga's paying, you don't need to know.
你说你要真正的车手
You just said you wanted real drivers.
真正的车手知道自己车里有什么
A real driver knows exactly what's in his car.
真正的车手
Mira, real driver,
没人逼你去开车
nobody's forcing you to race.
你是老大？
You the boss?
还是我和老大说话？
Or am I talking to the boss?
我看着像老大吗？
Do I look like a boss?
我的工作是找到最好的车手
My job is to find the best drivers, period.
谁赢得比赛谁就能知道 好不好？
Whoever wins the race gets the info. We cool?
好不好？
Are we cool?
好吧
Yeah, we're cool.
不太好
No, we ain't cool, man.
谁封闭街道？
Who's closing these streets?
没人 这是关键
No one. That's the point.
导路下载中 请等待
PIease wait whiIe directions are downIoaded.
到加亮路线
Proceed to the highlighted route.
十
Ten,
九
nine,
八
eight,
七
seven,
六…
six...
- 你确定这么做？ - 很多事情变了
- You sure you want to do this? - A lot has changed.
四…  说得没错
...four... You're right.
…三
...three,
二
two,
一
one,
出发！
go!
前方右转
Right turn ahead.
距离目标5英里
You are now five miIes from your destination.
我的屁股怎么样 小子？
How's my ass look, Chia Pet?
犹太杂种
Ghetto Smurf.
去死吧
Dead man driving.
快啊！
Come on!
前方右转
Right turn ahead.
靠！
Shit!
见鬼
Damn.
重新计算路线
Rerouting.
前方直行
Proceed straight ahead.
重新计算路线
Rerouting.
靠
Shit.
- 重新计算路线 - 闭嘴！
- Rerouting. - Just shut up!
距离目标2.6英里
You are 2.6 miIes from destination.
啊…没看到
Oops, I didn't see you.
距离目标4.5英里
You are now four and one-haIf miIes from your destination.
- U型转弯 可能的话 - 开玩笑吧？
- U-turn, if possible. - Are you kidding me?
距离目标4.2英里
You are now 4.2 miIes from your destination.
对不住了 爱车
Sorry, car.
距离目标1英里
You are now one miIe from your destination.
猜猜谁回来了 多姆？
Yeah, guess who's back, Dom?
加速！
Let's go!
车不错 宝贝！
Nice car, baby!
贱人！
Bitch!
距离目标四分之一英里
You are now one-quarter mile from your destination.
太早啦 多姆
Too early, Dom.
不！
No!
还是个菜鸟
Still a buster.
到达目的地 再见
You have reached your destination. Goodbye.
至少你不耍赖赢不了我
At least we know you can't beat me straight up.
我不知道规则一说
I didn't know there were any rules.
这就是我说的真正的车手
Now that's what I call real driving.
胡说八道！
No, that's bullshit, man!
向你妈妈哭去吧
Go cry to your mama, eh?
你现在为布拉加工作了
You work for Braga now.
GPS呼叫时 你就跟着走
When the GPS calls, you follow.
驾驶执照
Driver's license.
什么驾驶执照？
What driver's license?
大拇指
Thumb.
手机号码
Cell phone number.
指纹是给坎波斯的
The print is for Campos.
号码是给我的
The number is for me.
脓包！
Yo, nutsack!
告诉你吧 那个肌肉男总能打败新来的
Let me tell you something, man, muscle beats import every time.
你听清了？总能打败！
You know what I'm saying? Every time!
姑娘们 回到德怀特叔叔这来吧
Ladies, let's get on back to Papa Dwight's.
德怀特叔叔要你们脱鞋
Papa Dwight wants you to take off your shoes.
德怀特喜欢美脚 脱鞋吧
Dwight likes feet. Take off your shoes.
真美
So beautiful.
德怀特太喜欢了
Dwight likes this foot a lot.
宝贝！
Yes, baby!
- 德怀特喜欢… - 联邦调查局的
- Daddy Dwight loves... - FBl!
我什么都没做 德怀特什么都没做！
I didn't do nothing, man! Dwight didn't do nothing!
- 别走！你们去哪？ - 再见了 德怀特！
- Hey, no! Stay, stay! Where you going? - Bye, Dwight!
我做了什么？
No, what did I do?
你因为私藏毒品被捕
You're under arrest for distribution of meth.
毒品？我从不碰那玩意
Meth? Dwight's never touched that shit, bro!
现在碰了
Dwight has now.
那不是我的！
Yo, that ain't mine! No!
你知道这从来站不住脚的 对吧？
You know that's never gonna stick, right?
是啊
Yeah, it's not supposed to.
加油！
Live it up! Live it up!
科罗娜啤酒
Yeah, Corona.
德怀特太不幸了
That's too bad about Dwight.
你进入他们组织那晚联邦调查局 搜查了他的房子
Having the Feds raid your house the same night you make the team.
真不幸
So unfortunate.
我想说我真没想到在这遇见你
I wish I could say I was surprised to see you here.
怎样才能让我不告诉他们你是警察
What's to stop someone from telling them you're a cop?
和我不告诉他们你来这的真正目的 是一回事吧
Probably the same thing that's keeping me from telling them why you're really here.
- 你们好吗 伙计们 - 你好
- What up, fellows? - Hey, how you doing?
- 玩得开心吗？ - 很开心
- Great. You having a good time? - Yeah, a great time.
跟我来 找点乐子
Come on, let's have a better time.
你的车怎么样了？撞得不轻啊
How's your car? It took a nasty bump.
会好的
lt'll be ready.
我听说你刚从牢里出来
I also heard you just got out of County.
嗯
Yeah. Mmm-hmm.
听说过吉姆・加西亚吗？
You know a guy named Jim Garcia?
没有 地方大 很多名字 很多面孔
Nah. Big place. Lots of names, lots of faces.
你 很多人要抓你
And you, you're wanted by a lot of people, homes.
那可对生意不好
Yeah, that kind of heat can't be good for business.
那要看你怎么看这件事
Yeah, well, that depends on how you look at things.
我被抓 我坐牢
I go down, I do time.
真的坐牢
I do real time.
我不知道别人怎么样 只要我看到后面警车在追
I don't know about your other drivers, but when I see flashing lights in my mirror,
我可不会停
I don't stop.
你们两个认识吗？
Do you know each other?
他曾泡我妹妹
He used to date my sister.
明白了
I see.
- 你很走运 - 怎讲？
- You're a lucky man. - How's that?
你还活着
You're still breathing.
为我们爱过和失去过的女人们干杯
To the ladies we've loved and the ladies we've lost.
布拉加怎么样？
So, what's Braga about?
他和我们一样
You know, he's just one of us.
发迹于街头 最后入狱
Came up from the streets. Down for el barrio.
现在他是发号施令的人
Now he's a shot caller.
老大中的老大
The boss of bosses.
瞧见这些人了吗？
See all these cats in here?
他们都愿意为布拉加去死
Any one of them would die for Braga.
包括你？
lncluding you?
特别是我
Especially me.
好好玩 伙计们 这是你们的地盘
Enjoy the party, fellows. Club's yours.
不管你们要什么 美酒 佳人 都行
Whatever you want, booze, broads, it's all good.
布拉加是我的
Braga's mine.
我要把他们一网打尽
I'm taking the whole house down.
好运
Good luck.
对这辆车很感兴趣？
Something interests you about this car?
欣赏车身设计
Just admiring the body work.
你是那种喜欢车胜过女人的人吗？
Are you one of those boys who prefers cars to women?
我是那种喜欢完美身形的人 不管是车还是女人
I'm one of those boys that appreciates a fine body, regardless of the make.
你的车？
Your car?
菲尼克斯的车
It's Fenix's car.
你会在接头地点见到他 他给你们领路
You'll meet him at the rendezvous. He'll be leading you.
现在…
So now
我知道了你对车的品味
that I know your taste in cars,
告诉我 你的女人什么样子？
tell me, what about your women?
一切都是从眼睛开始的
It all starts with the eyes.
她那双眼睛能穿过浮夸的外表
She's got to have those kind of eyes that can look right through the bullshit
看到一个人的本质
to the good in someone.
二分天使 八分魔鬼
20% angel, 80% devil.
来到人间
Down to earth.
一点都不怕指甲上沾上机油
Ain't afraid to get a little engine grease under her fingernails.
听起来一点都不像我
That doesn't sound anything like me.
是的
It ain't.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
- 送你个礼物 - 好啊
- I got a gift for you. - All right.
脏酒杯 我一直想要的
A dirty shot glass, just what I always wanted.
我昨晚从俱乐部弄来的
I got these from the club last night.
他们两个的指纹都在上面
There's two sets of prints here. Run them both.
我知道一个是坎波斯的 另一个很可能是布拉加的
I know one of these is Campos'. I think the other might be Braga's.
你要联系国际刑警组织
And you're gonna have to go beyond lnterpol.
那意味着我要联系每一位探员
So, that means I have to contact individual agencies,
这要好几周时间 好吧
and that could take weeks. Okay.
喂
Yeah.
不到3个街区你就3次违章了
That's your third traffic violation in less than three blocks.
慢点 奥康纳
Slow it down, O'Conner.
没问题 老爹
Sure thing, Dad.
他停下了
He stopped.
我们跟丢了
We lost him.
他关掉了跟踪器 我们还不知道
He killed the tracker. We don't know that.
我告诉你 他关掉了跟踪器 我们还不知道！
I'm telling you, he killed the tracker. We don't know that yet!
直升机出动
Get the bird overhead.
正向北飞行 33度56分
Right now, I'm moving north, 33', 56'...
安全
All clear.
呼叫总部
Base, fIag nine, I'm at AngeIs 5.
没发现目标 重复 没发现目标
I don't have a taIIy on the target. Repeat, I don't have a taIIy on the target.
他们走了 那下面没人
They're gone, there's no one down there.
见鬼！
Damn it!
这不对 老兄 没人说过被锁在卡车里
This ain't right, bro. Nobody said nothing about being locked in no truck.
怎么回事
Tell me about it.
嘿 嘿！
Hey. Hey!
你认为他们带我们去哪？
Yo! Where do you think they're taking us?
无所谓
Don't matter.
我们现在只是凑热闹的
We're all just along for the ride now.
欢迎来到墨西哥 小伙子们
Welcome to Mexico, boys.
直升机和监视摄像头
There are helicopters and surveillance cameras
扫描边界的热信号
that scan for heat signatures at the border.
但是存在盲点 通过卫星我可以引导你们穿过去
But there are blind spots that I can guide you through via satellite.
绝对不能犯错 因此你们必须遵守指示
There can be no margin of error, so you must follow my every direction.
有问题吗？
Any questions?
我认为菲尼克斯会在那
I thought Fenix was gonna be here.
他在外面等你们
He'll meet you out there.
好啦 大家同步
All right, everybody, sync up.
好运 先生们
Good luck, gentlemen.
卫星已连接
SateIIite Iinkup engaged.
以当前速度前往北部边界
Keep proceeding northbound at current speed.
跟紧菲尼克斯
Stay cIose to Fenix.
他将带你们穿过边境
He'II Iead you across.
隆加多峡谷北侧发现热信号
I got a heat signature northbound along Legardo Ravine.
墨西哥一侧的热信号窗口要关闭45秒
Thermal imaging window on the Mexico side's gonna be down for about 45 seconds.
使用摄像头
Get the camera on it.
人工操作 设定摄像头到指定坐标
Manual override. Rerouting camera to designated coordinates.
快点 你们被盯上了
Hurry it up. You guys have been tagged.
糟糕
Shit.
特伦托 获取背后情况
Toretto, get back in formation.
重新成像开始
Reimaging commencing.
什么都没发现
I don't see anything.
他们跑掉了
They're gone.
派直升机去监视
Get the helicopters to cover it.
总部 我们离开隆加多峡谷40秒
Base, we're 40 seconds out from Legardo Ravine.
他们派了直升机
They're sending a heIicopter.
你们有30秒时间
You have 30 seconds.
北纬32度33分 西经116度49分
North 32' 33', west 1 1 6' 49'.
窗口很快就要关闭
The window is cIosing fast.
你们要在他们派出地面支援之前离开那
You need to get out of there before they send ground support.
15秒
Fifteen seconds.
总部 距离目标2英里
Base, target is at two miIes.
你们没时间了
You're running out of time.
你们快离开那！
You need to get out now!
总部 我们在北纬32度33分 西经116度49分
Base, we're at north 32' 33', west 116' 49'.
没发现目标 出动地面部队以确认
We have no visuaI contact. RoII ground units for confirmation.
慢！
Sloppy!
太慢了！
Very sloppy!
你在做什么？
What are you doing, man?
快点
Come on.
出来
Get out.
快点
Come on, man.
快点 我们走
Come on, today, man. Come on, let's go.
嘿 别碰我！嘿 别碰我！
Hey, don't touch me. Hey, don't touch me, man!
我说别碰我！
Hey, I said don't touch me, man!
把手从我身上拿开
Hey, look, dawg, don't put your hands on me.
马利克
Hey, Malik, chill, bro.
你们怎么回事？
Yo, man, what's up with your boy?
嘿 老大！
Hey, boss man!
你说什么？
What did you say?
我说只有脓包用硝基甲烷
I said only pussies run nitrometh.
你检查过我的车？
You looked under my hood?
在和你说话呢
I'm talking to you.
你在想什么？
Got something on your mind?
70款普利茅斯
'70 Plymouth.
她叫莱蒂
Her name was Letty.
Yo.
我的钱呢？
Where's my money?
有人撞毁了她的车
And somebody wrecked her car.
我撞的
I wrecked her car.
你还记得那张脸吗？
You remember her face?
嗯？
Huh?
我可忘了
'Cause I don't.
上次我见到它 在燃烧
Last time I saw it, it was burning.
现在又怎样？
Now what?
我会享受接下来这一刻
I'm going to enjoy what happens next.
多姆 上车！
Dom, get in!
快上车！
Get in! Come on!
快点！快上车！
Come on! Get in the fucking car! Let's go! Hurry up!
发现了什么？
What have you got, Trinh?
我们在联系各国的特工
We're contacting agencies in multiple countries.
很不幸 他们大多数都要手动 扫描指纹上传
Unfortunately, most of them have to manually scan their prints for us to upload.
奥康纳在5号线
O'Conner's on line five.
长官 您看看这个
And, sir, you should see this.
谢谢
Thank you.
讲话 奥康纳
Talk to me, O'Conner.
- 你到底去哪了？ - 我拿到货了
- Where the hell have you been? - I got the shipment.
“我拿到货” 还是“我们拿到货”？
"l got the shipment," or "we got the shipment"?
你在说什么？
What are you taIking about?
交通监视器录到你和特伦托在一起的画面
Traffic cams in the area picked up pictures of you and Toretto together.
听者 奥康纳 把货带来 把特伦托带来
Listen to me, O'Conner. Bring in the shipment and bring in Toretto.
但我认为目标是布拉加 我们现在有机会
But I thought the point was to get Braga. We got an opportunity here.
布莱恩 没时间了
Brian, the clock stopped ticking.
把他们带来 明白吗？
Bring them in. Are we cIear?
奥康纳？
O'Conner?
六千万就是这样子
So this is what $60 million looks like.
嗯 你得去找医生看看
Yeah, we got to get you to a doctor.
我们要找个地方把它藏起来
We got to find a place to hide this.
我有个地方
I got a spot.
502号 酒后驾车 需要48小时扣押
502, wet reckless. I need a 48-hour hold.
找个地方吧
Out back. Any spot you can find.
这没问题吗？
You sure about this?
是的 他们最不会搜查的地方 就是自己的押车场 相信我吧
Yeah. The last place they'll check, their own impound yard. Trust me.
我在想…
You know, I've been thinking,
你炸毁你的车的时候 把我的也炸了
when you blew up your car back there, you blew up mine, too.
- 是吗？ - 嗯
- Yeah? - Yeah.
你欠我一辆跑车
So now you owe me a 1 0-second car.
- 是吗？ - 是的
- Is that right? - Yeah.
现在扯平了
Now we're even.
你就这样让我离他远点？
Is this your way of keeping me away from him?
- 你是我唯一能求助的人 - 他是我哥哥 当然
- You're the only one I could call. - He's my brother, of course.
子弹不在里面
The bullet's not in there.
我要清洗干净然后缝上 会有点疼
I'm gonna clean it and stitch it up. It's going to hurt.
我打赌你很享受这个
I bet you're going to enjoy this.
有点
A little.
- 要这个吗？ - 嗯
- Want some of this? - Yeah.
辣的
It's spicy.
我很喜欢
I like it hot.
多姆 你怎么了？
Dom, what are you doing?
你太着急了 要先祈祷的
You reached first, you have to say grace.
感谢上帝
Thank you, Lord, for blessing this table.
赐给我们食物 家庭和友情
With food, family and friendship.
你问我为什么放走多姆
You asked me why I let Dom go.
我想是因为那个时刻
I think it's because at that moment,
我尊重他胜过我自己
I respected him more than I did myself.
嗯
Yeah.
我从多姆身上学到的是 什么都不重要 除非你有准则
One thing I learned from Dom is that nothing really matters unless you have a code.
你的准则是什么 布莱恩？
And what's your code, Brian?
正在找呢
I'm working on it.
不好 嘿 多姆
Shit. Hey, Dom.
- 你打算什么时候告诉我？ - 多姆 你在做什么？
- When were you gonna tell me? - Dom, what are you doing?
你打算什么时候告诉我 是你在背后指使莱蒂？
When were you gonna tell me you were running Letty?
- 让我解释… - 你打算什么时候…
- Let me explain... - When were you gonna...
多姆 住手！
Dom, stop!
- 你不明白 - 我不明白？
- You don't understand. - I don't understand?
住手！
Stop!
她是为了…
She did it for...
多姆 住手！
Dom, stop!
住手！拜托！
Dom, stop it! Please stop!
她是为你 多姆！为你！
She did it for you, Dom! She did it for you!
莱蒂来找我要以为布拉加运货 来交换把你的名字从名单上除去
Letty came to me to clear your name in exchange for bringing down Braga.
她是为了让你回家！
She just wanted you to come home!
对不起 多姆！
I'm sorry, Dom!
对不起！
I'm sorry!
你最好有个解释 你直接违抗命令
You better have one hell of an explanation. You disobeyed a direct order.
- 货在哪？ - 很安全
- Where's the shipment? - It's safe.
安全
It's safe.
听者 我们可以拿这批货在媒体宣传
Look, we could use the shipment to parade in front of the media,
说是从街头查获了几百磅海洛因
get a few hundred pounds of heroin off the street,
但是布拉加以后还会运更多的货进来
but Braga's just gonna send another shipment next week and the week after that.
我们用这批货把布拉加引出来
Let's use the shipment to lure Braga out
把他们的头抓住
and lop the head off a multi-billion dollar cartel.
我们怎样做？
And how do you suggest we do that?
和布拉加面对面交易
A hand-to-hand exchange with Braga.
他从不出现
He'll never show.
他不得不露面
He can't afford not to.
你有计划吗？
You got a plan?
我们谈个交易
There's a price.
我们抓住布拉加 你放了特伦托
We bag Braga, you let Toretto walk.
- 喂 - 我是多姆
- Yes? - It's Dom.
我正想你呢
I was just thinking about you.
我给你我的号码的时候 希望你能打过来
You know, when I gave you my number, I was hoping you'd call.
但不是这种情况下
But not under these circumstances.
什么情况下？我活着？
What circumstances? Me being alive?
别对个人
Don't take it personaIIy.
这是公事
It's just business.
我自己有点公事
I got some business of my own.
让坎波斯接电话
Get Campos.
是他们
It's them.
嗯
Uh-huh.
布拉加就这样表现诚意？ 卸磨杀驴？
Was that how Braga inspires loyalty? Killing his drivers?
总能找到更多的车手
One can always find more drivers.
这是个好生意
It's just good business.
我要做笔交易
I want to trade.
布拉加从不谈判
Braga doesn't negotiate.
好吧
Fine.
你向他解释六千万的货怎么就不见了
You explain to him how all of a sudden $60 million worth of product disappears.
我知道这对生意可不好
I know that can't be good for business.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
六百万现金 布拉加亲自送过来
Six million cash, delivered by Braga himself.
我可不想当靶子
I don't Iike being shot at.
我可不想冒生命危险 除非他也冒险前来
I ain't gonna put my neck out again unless he's got something to lose, too.
他不会来的
He'll never go for it.
或者我和布拉加打交道 或者你去
Either I deal with Braga, or you do.
时间和地点？
When and where?
队员已经就位 周围待命
Sir, players are onsite. Holding positions at the perimeter.
听者 所有人待命
All right. Listen up. Everybody stay frosty.
接到奥康纳信号前不得行动
We don't move a muscIe untiI O'Conner gives the signaI.
他拿到钱的时候 我们知道该怎么办
When he gets the money, you know what to do.
好消息是 我们抓住这家伙时
Well, the good news is, when we get this guy,
你就自由了
you walk out of here a free man.
他们这样和你说的？
Is that what they told you?
是的 这是协议
Yeah, that's the deal.
你还信圣诞老人这回事？
You still put milk and cookies out for Santa Claus?
是啊
Yeah.
来了
Here.
以防万一
ln case things go shitty.
像以前一样？
Just like old times?
嗯
Yeah.
你掉东西了
You dropped something.
- 这就是你想要的？ - 多姆…
- That's what you wanted, - right? Dom...
他没恶意 别担心
He's harmless. Don't worry about him.
他真的为莱蒂遗憾
And he's really sorry about Letty.
我们的货呢？
Where's our stuff?
曾经在这里面的货吗？
You mean the stuff that used to be in here, right?
我们见到布拉加 你就能见到货 这是协议
Well, you'll see it when we see Braga. That was the deal.
别担心
No worries.
布拉加守信的
Braga keeps his word.
二百万
$2 million.
我拿到我的东西后给你们剩下的钱
You get the rest when I get my property.
- 斯特萨克 - 我们找到匹配了
- Stasiak. - We got a match.
指纹100%是布拉加的
The fingerprint's Braga's 1 00%.
正等待传真面部确认
Just waiting on faciaI confirmation via fax.
我有个问题
I got a question for you.
你越狱时候穿的是粉的？
You wearing pink when you were clawing your way out of el barrio?
所有特警准备行动
Order all agents to move in.
我们得到确认 头号疑犯身着灰色西装
We got confirmation. Primary suspect wearing gray suit.
行动
Let's move.
长官 奥康纳还没给出信号
Sir, O'Conner hasn't given us the signal yet.
你哪部分不明白？ 我们刚得到确认 快行动！
What part of that didn't you understand? We just got confirmation. Do it!
头号疑犯身着灰色西装 重复！
Secure primary suspect in gray suit. Repeat!
头号疑犯身着灰色西装
Secure primary suspect in gray suit.
你在想我在想什么 对吧？
You're thinking what I'm thinking, right?
他不是布拉加
He ain't Braga.
糟糕
Oh, shit.
放下武器！联邦调查局的！
Drop your weapons! FBl!
趴下！
Get down!
离开这！
Get out of here!
离开这 多姆！
Get out of here, Dom!
撞死他
Run him down.
快走！
Go!
坎波斯就是布拉加！
Campos is Braga!
快走
Come on.
接近头号目标中
Approaching primary target.
疑犯安全
Primary suspect is secure.
全程他都在你们鼻子底下
He was under your nose the whoIe time.
现在布拉加跑了
Now Braga's escaped.
特伦托向南边跑了 很可能越过了边界
Toretto's heading south, probably long across the border by now.
你知道你惹了什么麻烦吗 奥康纳先生？
Do you have any idea the kind of trouble you're in, O'Conner?
我在做我的工作
I was doing my job.
他不是第一个你协助逃脱法律制裁的人
He ain't the first bad guy you helped escape the law's grasp.
你被停职了
As of now, you're being taken off active duty,
直到举行正式听证会
until this house can mount a formal inquiry.
布拉加呢？
What about Braga?
你不用再操心了
That's no longer your concern.
我们知道了布拉加在哪
We now know where Braga is, right?
海关通过卫星追踪他到他的老巢 墨西哥的台卡利
Customs tracked him via satellite to his home base in Tecali, Mexico.
我们在墨西哥没有执法权
Mexico is out of our jurisdiction.
事实是
The fact is
官员们忙着召开新闻发布会解释这次抓捕
the brass will be so busy holding press conferences over the seizure,
我们在背后行动
we'll skate under the radar.
我认为我们的工作是做正确的事情
I thought we signed on to do the right thing.
大家都在找你
Everyone's looking for you.
我就在这
I'm right here.
很高兴看到你走出往事
It's nice to see you've gone with the times
换成了电子燃料注入 看上去不错
and switched to electronic fuel injection. Looks good.
菜鸟成专家了
Buster became a gearhead.
我和你去
I'm going with you.
我没打算带任何人回来
I don't plan on bringing anyone back.
我知道
I know.
按下阀门
Hit that throttle.
嘿
Hey.
你怎样和你唯一的哥哥道别？
How do you say goodbye to your only brother?
你不需要
You don't.
我以为你不会出现的
I thought you weren't gonna show up.
你救了我的命
You saved my life.
我想还你个情
I'm willing to return the favor.
这会帮你找到布拉加
This will help get you to Braga.
多姆
Dom.
去那是自杀
Going in there is suicide.
我别无选择
I have no choice.
你一定很爱她
You must have loved her very much.
我的权力到这就结束了
So this is where my jurisdiction ends.
我的才刚开始
And this is where mine begins.
- 欢迎来到布拉加阁下的房子 - 别担心 神父 一切都会好起来的
- welcome to the house of the lord, Sr.Braga. - Don't worry father, everthing's go.
帮我们去天堂
To help us get to heaven.
请接收这份祝福
Please receive this blessing.
你不会被宽恕的
You ain't forgiven.
你们要逮捕我？
You boys want to arrest me?
在这里？
...in here.
不 远不止
No, we're beyond that.
这次你跑不了了
You can't buy your way out of this one.
你和我…
You and me...
你和我没什么不同
You and me, we're not so different.
你不是英雄
You're no hero.
说得没错
You're right.
所以你逃回了边界
And that's why you're going back across the border.
菲尼克斯是我的
But Fenix is mine.
没问题
You got it.
不好！
Shit!
如果你能跑出两英里 算你走运
You'll make it a couple of miles out, if you're lucky.
你知道你要去哪吗？
You know where you're going?
想借我的GPS？
You want to borrow my GPS?
你的人呢？
Where are your boys at?
还出不出现？
Are they going to show up or what?
你得小心点
Careful what you ask for.
停车 停车吧
Just stop. Just stop the car.
别打着老板 笨蛋
Don't shoot the boss, idiots.
就在你后面
Right behind you.
多姆 前往隧道 我们利用隧道
Dom, head to the tunnel. Let's use the tunnel.
离开这 布莱恩
Get out of here, Brian.
你确定知道隧道在哪？确定吗？
You sure you know where the tunnels are? You sure?
是的 我会抓紧点
Yeah. I'd hold on.
这可能会疼
This might hurt.
现在到我的地盘了 宝贝
You're in my world now, baby!
就这样 宝贝！前面没路了
That's it, baby! End of the road.
现在想怎样？
Now what?
玩完了
Game over.
不
No, no, no.
快点！
Come on!
嘿！
Hey!
那我弄出来！
Get me out of here!
脓包
Pussy.
我看看
Let me see that.
压住
Yeah. Just keep pressure there.
你会没事的
You'll be all right.
你得离开这
You gotta get out of here.
我不再逃跑了
I ain't running anymore.
我问你件事
I gotta ask you something.
嗯？
Yeah?
你知道如果你不作弊 那次赛车我就赢了 对吧
You know I would have won that race if you didn't cheat, right?
你头撞得不轻吧
You hit your head hard.
别让我笑了
Don't make me laugh.
全体起立
All rise.
请坐
Please be seated.
请起立 特伦托先生
Please rise, Mr. Toretto.
我听了证词
I've listened to the testimony
特别考虑了
and taken into special consideration
奥康纳探员为特伦托先生的请愿
Agent O'Conner's appeal of clemency on behalf of Mr. Toretto.
他的行为直接导致大毒枭
That his actions directly resulted in the apprehension
阿图罗・布拉加的被捕
of known drug trafficker Arturo Braga.
但是
However,
司法部认为
this judiciary finds that
一件正确的事不能弥补一生犯下的错
one right does not make up for a lifetime worth of wrongs.
因此
And as such,
我不得不按加州法律判最终刑期
I find that I am forced to level the maximum sentence under California law.
多米尼克・特伦托
Dominic Toretto,
你被判在隆波克监狱
you are hereby sentenced to serve 25 years to life
最高安全等级监禁25年
at the Lompoc maximum security prison system
不得假释
without the possibiIity of earIy paroIe.
休庭
This court is adjourned.